# Shervin Sahba

ssahba@uw.edu ✓ 401.374.1533 resume updated 2019-07-10

Hi! I'm a Physics PhD student at the University of Washington in the Kutz Research Group working on data-driven discovery in physical systems, often for photonics research. My work at UW extends to teaching undergraduate courses and volunteering to build instructional, community, and mentorship programs. I am interested in opportunities in data science, software development, and theoretical or computational physics.

Links: 

ResearchGate — in LinkedIn — 

GoogleScholar

Outside of a professional context, I enjoy climbing, lifting, bicycling, chess, game dev, writing music, and Linux.

## Education University of Washington

PhD Physics Student (Advisor: Nathan Kutz)

MS Physics, 2018.

#### Coursera

Advanced Machine Learning Specialization (ongoing)

## San Francisco State University

MS Physics (Advisor: Weining Man), Distinguished Achievement Award.

## **UC Berkeley Extension**

Certification in Information Systems, 2013. Received with 4.0 Distinction.

#### University of Rhode Island

BA Psychology, 2009.

BS Supply Chain & Logistical Management, 2009.

BS Entrepreneurial Management, 2009. Magna Cum Laude.

# Research & Publications

MS Thesis: "Experimental Measures on Anisotropic Photonic Structures

and Computational Tuning of Photonic Systems"

Sellers, S., Man, W., Sahba, S., & Florescu, M., Nature Communications (Feb. 2017) "Local Self-Uniformity in Photonic Networks." doi:10.1038/ncomms14439

## Presentations ARCS NCC Symposium, Poster, "Hyperuniform Disordered Photonic Structures," 2016.

ARCS NCC SFSU Review, Powerpoint, "Photonic Crystals and Modern Applications," 2015.

## Honors First Year Graduate Teaching Award, University of Washington, 2019.

Physics Department Fellowship, University of Washington, 2017.

Distinguished Achievement Award, San Francisco State University, 2017.

ARCS Northern California Scholar, 2016-2017.

Blue Waters Petascale Institute, Selected participant, UIUC, 2016.

COSE Student Project Showcase Winner, 1st place in physical sciences, SFSU, 2016.

ARCS Northern California Scholar, 2015-2016.

Magna Cum Laude, University of Rhode Island, 2009.

American Invitational Mathematics Examination, Invited contestant, 2005.

Community & Affiliations

**Software Carpentry** 

Instructor, 2019.

Career Development Organization for Physicists at UW

Conference organizer, President, 2017-2019.

DRiP (Directed Reading in Physics) Program

Program organizer and instructor, 2018-2019.

Physics Graduate Student Committee

Event committee member, 2018-2019.

**UW Physics Peer Mentor Program** 

Peer mentor, 2018-2019.

**OSA**, The Optical Society

SFSU Student Chapter President, 2016-2017. Member, 2017-2019.

Programming Languages

Top-tier: Python, Julia, MATLAB, Shell, Mathematica, Git

Mid-tier: C, C++, C#, Scheme, SQL.

Computer Skills

ML: Tensorflow, Keras, PyTorch, Scikit

physics: Lumerical, meep, mpb

graphics: Blender, Photoshop, Krita, GIMP

systems: Linux (Manjaro, Arch, Debian, Ubuntu, ...), Windows

productivity: IATEX, Slack, Discord, Jupyter, Github, Sublime, Office, Google Suite

web: Jekyll, WordPress game dev: Godot, Unity

Languages

English, Persian, Spanish

Teaching Experience

Dept. Physics, University of Washington

Teaching Assistant, 2017 - 2019

PHYS115 General Physics Mechanics

PHYS116 General Physics Electromagnetism PHYS117 General Physics Mechanics Lab

PHYS118 General Physics Electromagnetism Lab (2 sections)

PHYS121 Physics w/ Calc. Mechanics Tutorial (4 sections)

PHYS122 Physics w/ Calc. Electromagnetism Tutorial (2 sections)

PHYS123 Physics w/ Calc. Waves & Optics Tutorial PHYS121z Physics w/ Calc. Mechanics Lab (2 sections)

PHYS224 Thermodynamics

PHYS324 Quantum Mechanics (4 sections)

PHYS325 Quantum Mechanics PHYS423 Solid State Physics

PHYS427 Quantum Computing & Information

Teaching Experience (continued)

## Dept. Physics & Astronomy, San Francisco State University

Teaching Assistant, 2015

PHYS360 Electricity and Magnetism PHYS457 Principles of Electronics

#### Elite Educational Institute

Mathematics & Physics Instructor, 2014-2017.

Private Tutoring: SAT, SAT II, Precalculus, AP Calculus, AP Physics. Courses: Geometry, Precalculus (2 sections), SAT Prep (10 sections)

## Edge U Tutoring (link to archived site)

Founder & Private Tutor, 2013-2015.

Private Tutoring: SAT, ACT, AP Calculus, AP Physics, AP Biology

## **Revolution Prep**

SAT Instructor & Private Tutor, 2010-2013.

Courses: SAT Prep (19 sections), AP Phys B Review Course, Online SAT Prep (3 sections)